你好，非常感谢你
hello and thank you very much
我的名字是卢卡斯-阿特金森
my name is Lucas taken Atkinson
我代表 "滚动js "发言。
and I'm speaking on behalf of roll up js
所以我认为这是
so I think it is
我认为可以这样说，卷积
fair to say that roll up
是一个基础，而
is one of the foundations that
beat的基础之一。
beat is built upon
当我被邀请时，至少有一个人
and when I was invited there was at least one person
他希望我能够
who expected me to
阐明这种关系的更多信息
shed a little more light on this relationship
是的，我稍后会谈及这张床
and yes I will talk about that bed later
首先我想谈的是另一件事
first I want to talk about something else entirely
但他们是和我一起的
but they are with me
这将是相关的
it will be relevant
对维生素也是如此
for vit as well
我想说的是
what I want to talk about
是
is
我们有一个非常老的滚筒包，已经有相当长一段时间了
a very old roller pack that we had for quite some time
它就是这个
and it is this one
大块的哈希值应该是基于输出的
chunk hashes should be based on the output
这是从2009年5月开始的
it's from may 2009
正如你所看到的，它仍然是开放的
as you see it's still open
是的，它是一种关键
and yes it is kind of critical
它是足够关键的
it is critical enough
因此，一个著名的谷歌开发人员edocat
so that one well known Google developer edocat
是真的做了一个伟大的
was really making a great
的情况下，rollop的插件系统是优越的
case that rollop's plugin system is superior
的替代品
to the alternatives
是引用它作为
was citing it as
的
the
他发现roll up最重要的问题是
the most important issue he found with roll up
散列发生在错误的时间
hashing happens at the wrong time
这可能导致不好的兑现
which can lead to bad cashing
和
and
这到底是怎么回事？
what is this all about
先生
sir
要理解这一点，你需要了解
to understand that you need to understand
基于内容的火名
content based fire names
所以这个想法是
so the idea is
我们使用
that we use
火名有一些东西，我们称之为哈希值
fire names that have something that we call a hash
的内容在其名称中
of the content in its name
这样，它们就是其内容的唯一标识符。
so that they are unique identifiers for their content
所以在这个例子中
so in this example
我有一个可以动态导入其他块的块
I have a chunk that dynamically imports to other chunks
如果我改变了右上角的块的内容
if I were to change something in the upper right chunk
比方说，我们正在记录其他东西
let's say we are logging something else
那么这将意味着该块的哈希值会
then this would mean the hash of that chunk would
变化，这意味着左边的主块中的导入
change that means the import
在左边的主块中也会改变
in the main chunk on the left would also change
这也会导致
which would also lead
主块的哈希值发生变化
the hash of the main chunk to change
和
and
就是这样
that is it
所以
so
为什么这很重要，为什么我们要这样做
why is this important why do we want to do that
如果我们有财务上的唯一标识符
if we have finances unique identifiers
我们就可以配置我们的服务
we can configure our service
以
to
使用非常长的兑现时间
use very long cashing time
这样，浏览器的现金就会保留这些
so that the browser cash retains the
文件基本上是无限期的
files basically indefinitely
并且不需要再从服务器上调取它们
and they don't need to be pulled again from the server
而我们仍然有能力在任何时候进行部署
while we still have the ability to deploy at any time
因为改变内容就意味着改变下降
because changing the content means changing the falling
的好处是，在这个例子中
with the advantage that in this example the
在这个例子中，较低的骑行块没有变化
lower ride chunk which is unchanged
仍然可以从现金中获取
can still be taken from the cash
这听起来很简单，但是
this sounds kind of straightforward but
如果你有循环引用会怎么样
what happens if you have circular references
这并不罕见
which is not too uncommon
所以
so
想象一下，你正在使用
imagine you are using
一些路由解决方案
some routing solution
那么通常路由器会动态地导入
then usually the router will dynamically import
当你改变页面时，其他块会被动态导入
other chunks when you change pages
其他块是什么？
are the other chunks or reference the routers
你有一个循环参考
you have a circular reference
路由器和所有其他分块之间的循环参考。
between the router and all other chunks
所以在我的例子中
so in my example
我只是在我的两个块之间进行动态导入
I'm just having dynamic imports between my 2 chunks
我怎样才能为它创建一个哈希值呢？
how do I create a hash for that
当他们的
when their
火的大陆
continent of the fire
将取决于另一个文件的哈希值
would depend on the hash of the other file
一种方法是
one approach could be
说好吧，那我们就散列所有的东西
to say okay then we hash everything
除了另一个文件的哈希值
except the hash of the other file
然后把2个点卷起来
and the way roll up 2 dots
这只是对原始文件的散列
this is just hashing the original files
与原来的导入目标在一起
with the original import targets in place
所以在我的例子中，我们使用表情符号作为哈希值
so in my examples we are using emojis as hashes
因为它更容易看到
because it's kind of easier to see
而且
and
你不需要记住
you don't have to memorize
数字和字母
numbers and letters
然后我们所做的是
and then what we do is
我们基本上是在创建一个哈希值的依赖图
we're basically creating a dependency graph of hashes
在这个例子中，我们知道
in this example we know
我们知道
that the
苹果块参考了西兰花块
apple chunk is kind of referencing the broccoli chunk
所以，苹果块的哈希值应该是苹果按
so the hash of the apple chunk should be apple press
西兰花在我的例子中是鱼
broccoli is fish in my example
而另一个区块的哈希值是
while the hash of the other chunk is
西兰花加苹果
broccoli plus apple
因为它发生在印度的错误矿石上。
because it happens to the wrong ore in India
顺序相反，说是我的鱿鱼
reverse order which say it's my squiddy
哈希
hash
然后作为最后一步
and then as a last step
我们将再次替换进口
we are replacing the imports again
用实际的块状名称
with the actual chunk names
现在，这些Chung
now these Chung
这些哈希值确实很可疑
these hashes are indeed very fishy
为什么会有猫腻呢？
why are they fishy
因为
because
我们希望在我们的数据集中有一个最小化的步骤
we want to have a minification step in our set
在我们改变进口之前，不可能发生最小化
a minification cannot happen before
我们改变进口
we change the imports
因为，在减法之后
because after midification
我们不会找到异国情调的人
we would not find the impotic
而且所有的东西都在移动
and everything has moved around
我们需要重新传递整个文件
we need to repass the entire file
而且还可能有一些东西被遗漏了
and it still may be possible that stuff is missing
或以完全不同的方式完成
or done in an entirely different way
所以发生的情况是
so what happens is
滚子把渲染块打成黑色
that roller brands the render chunk black
并在这之后进行勾选
and hook after that
这就改变了管道
which changes the conduit
但它不能改变哈希值
but it cannot change the hash
现在我们有不同的文件有相同的哈希值
and now we have different files that have the same hash
这基本上
which basically
破坏了我们对基于内容的所有假设
breaks all assumptions we have for content based
兑现
cashing
所以这个算法是很容易实现的
so this algorithm is kind of easy to implement
它可以处理周期
it handle cycles
但有一个问题是
but one drawberg was that
我们在内容哈希中有原始文件的目标
we had the original file aims in the content hashes
这很糟糕，因为
which is bad because
如果我重新命名文件
if I renamed the file
输出不会改变，但哈希值会改变
the output would not change but the hash would change
和
and
而
the
大问题是
big problem is that
大问题是，由插件进行的块状转换并不能
chunk transformation by plugins are not
处于改变哈希值的位置
in a position to change hashes
那么我们如何解决这个问题呢？
so how can we solve this issue
好吧，让我们回到
well let's go back
回到第一步
to the first step
因为这就是我们在第3卷中要做的事情
because that's what we're doing in roll up 3
所以假设
so assume
你有
you have
有2个机会互相参考
2 chance reference each other
所以我说好吧
so I said okay
我们希望有
we want to have
a
一个包含所有内容的哈希，但
a hash that contains everything but
块的哈希值
the chunk hash
我们想让它先运行渲染块
and we want it toto run render chunk first
所以我们要做的是把所有东西都替换成
so what we're doing is we're replacing everything with
占位符
placeholders
这些占位符有编号
the placeholders have numbered
数字对应于
the number correspondence to the
所以左边的是第一块
so the left is kind of chunk one
而右边的是第二块
and the right one is chunk 2
然后我们直接运行chunk cook的趋势
then we directly run the trend of chunk cook
它就会发挥它的魔力
which does its magic
所以这个例子，它只是改变了憧憬
so this example it just changes the longing
但它可以是任何东西
but it could be anything
它甚至可以改变进口
it could even change the import
或者完全删除导入的内容
or remove the import entirely
因为我们不做任何假设
and because we don't make assumptions
渲染的块是什么
what rendered chunk does
下一步，我们只是做一个全文搜索
the next step we're just doing a full text search
以找到输出中的所有占位符
to find all placeholders in the output
所以我们找到了我们的依赖关系，所以我们看到了chunk one
so then we find our dependencies so we see thechunk one
除了其中一个的内容
except for the content of one
它也依赖于占位符2
it also depends on placeholder 2
建议进一步
advice further
另一个块的版本
version for the other chunk
然后
then
我们
we
得到一个内容哈希值
to get a content hash
我们用84个占位符替换或占位符
we replace or placeholders with 84 placeholder
因为这些数字1 2他们是必需品
because those numbers one 2 they are necessaries
他们不能依赖于
they can't kind of depend on
一些竞赛条件
some race conditions
所以我们就得到了一个稳定的、只有内容的哈希值
so then we get a stable content only hash
而作为最后一步
and as a last step
我们现在正在计算文件散列，这给了我一个
we're now calculating the file hashes which gives me a
对和一个橙色的哈希值
pair and an orange hash
和
and
我们解决了这两个我们最初有
we solve these 2 we originally had
所以是的
so yes
我们有非常稳定的哈希值，只取决于内容
we have very stable hashes that only depend on content
我们可以有
we can have
在renderchang中进行任意的文件转换，即
arbitrary file transformations in renderchang that
增加进口，删除进口和
add imports remove imports and
由于这个特性
due to the nature of this
现在我们的renderchang cook有了一个很酷的新功能
we now have a cool new feature in our renderchang cook
中有了一个很酷的新功能，这也会让plugates受益。
which will also benefit beat plugates
这就是我们可以获得整个块状图。
which is we get the entire chunk graph available
所以有一个新的第四个参数来渲染chunk
so there's a new 4th parameter to render chunk
的第四个参数，它基本上包含一个所有
which basically contains a list of all
块的列表，以及它们的进口
chunks with their imports
专家以及他们之间的关系
experts and how they're related
现在这真的很酷
and now this is really cool
而且你也得到了非常好的反馈
and you also got very good feedback
从V的开发者那里
from the v developers
说它
that it
允许他们从小麦中去除大量的复杂性
allows them to remove a lot of complexity from wheat
这很好
and that's good
这让野草很高兴
that makes weed happy
但问题是，我们并不是为了小麦而这样做的
but the question is so we didn't do this for wheat
这样做是因为这是个严肃的银行
did this because this is a serious bank
但是，我们的关系究竟是怎样的？
but how is our relationship actually with beat
和
and
更准确地说，我们对杂草的感觉如何
more precisely how do we feel about weed
如果你从表面上看
than if you look from the surface
问安德鲁
asking Andrew
也许我们是
maybe we are
被珠子的成功所淹没了
slightly overwhelmed by the success of bead
这也给我们带来了很多新的问题。
which also put a lot of new issues for row of
特别是对插件来说
especially for the plugins
但如果你再深入一点
but if you go a little deeper
有更多的东西，要理解这一点
there is more to it and to understand this
问题是我们为什么
the question is why did we
为什么我们要选择卷起来？
choose roll up in the first place
所以我的理解是
so to my understanding
一个关键原因是插件系统
one key reason was the plugin system
所以，如果你重新使用一个现有的
so if you reuse an existing
插件系统来解决你的问题
plugin system that solves your purpose
你就能得到一个
you get access to a
广泛的插件
broad range of plugins
这意味着
which means
用户将更有可能采用
that users will be much more likely to adopt
你的解决方案，因为
your solution because
他们已经有
they already have
方法来适应他们的需求
ways to adapt them to their needs
另一方面，如果你
on the other hand if you
开发一个全新的插件系统
develop an entirely new plugin system
就不会有插件，除了少数几个
there will be no plugins except for a few
主的，那么用户就不会去
main one and then users will not go
而且你还需要用户来编写新的插件
and you also need the users to write new plugins
另一个原因显然是
another reason apparently
是，滚筒的操作者略小
was that roller operator slightly smaller
这也是我们引以为豪的地方
which is something that we pride upon
我仍然认为rollop有一个最好的
I still think that rollop has one of the best
我仍然认为rollop有一个最好的摇动树的算法
tree shaking algorithms out there
也许除了封闭式编译器，但它看起来并不是
maybe except for closure compiler but it didn't look
我们一直在努力使它变得更好。
reasonably where they are and we are
我们一直在努力使它变得更好
constantly working to make that better
而且我们有
and we have
显然，你的代码拆分方法
apparently a moment your code splitting approach
与es build相比
compared to es build
因此，这正是我们想要滚动起来的地方
so and this is exactly where we wanted roll up to be
我们为什么要在那里建立起一个滚动系统？
why did we want roll up to be there
所以要多了解一点背景
so a little more background going
进入我的个人历史
into my personal history
因此，滚动起来是
so roll up was
如你所知，是由Richeris开发的
developed as you may know by richeris
它是在2015年
it was in 2015
而在2017年，我
and in 2017 I
碰巧创造了一些可怜的请求来改善树
happened to create some poor requests to improve tree
晃动
shaking
的原因，因为我对这个话题感兴趣，并且
for reasons because I was interested in the topic and
在假释来源中寻找，我发现
looking in paroleup sources I found
一些改进的潜力
some potential for improvement
然后我就成了维护者
and then I kind of became maintainer
这就像富人说好吧这是
which was like rich saying okay this was
你在这里做的事情非常酷
very cool what you did here
为什么不直接合并你自己的东西呢？
why not just merge your own stuff
这里是版本库的轴心权利
here are the axis rights of the repository
是的
and yes
在那之后，他就不再合并我可怜的请求了
after that point he no longer merged my poor request
所以我在两个月后才知道
so I gathered after 2 months
也许我应该合并我自己可怜的请求
maybe I should merge my own poor request
然后他也没有再发布任何东西
and then he also did no longer release anything
所以我就说好吧，也许
so I I said okay maybe
你能把出版权给我吗？
can you give me the publishing rights
然后我就成了维护者
and then I was basically maintainer
这就是历史
and that's history
我觉得这对富人来说是好事
I think it was good for rich
因为
because
因为这时他已经在开发spelt了。
he was already developing on spelt at this time
但当然
but of course
作为一个维护者
being a maintainer
意味着你必须做出战略决策
means you have to make strategic decisions
卷轴应该放在哪里？
where should roll up go
我们没有一个庞大的团队
we do not have a large team
大多数贡献者都是单一时间的贡献者
most contributors are single time contributors
他们想拥有
who want to have
这个功能或那个功能
this feature or that feature
一个叫Bedford的人在很长一段时间内都是固定的贡献者
guy Bedford was for a longer time a regular contributor
那是非常好的
that was very nice
所以问题是
so the question is
应该专注于什么
what should be focus on
所以要关注的一件事
so one thing to focus on
我决定应该是核心改进
I decided should be core improvements
我们不希望轻易地扩大卷起的范围
we don't want to expand roll up scope lightly
坚持使用我们已经有的东西
to stick with the stuff that we already have
如果我们增加一个新的功能
and if we add a new feature
那么我们真的想确定
then we really want to be sure
这
that this
是一个我们要长期维护的功能
is a feature we are going to maintain for a long time
所以海岸洪水是你认为我们添加的一个功能
so coast flooding was one you think we added
还有
and there are
我们添加了很多小功能，但它们更多的是
lots of small features we added but they are more
使得这幅画
making the picture
完善画面，而不是
completing the picture than
真正扩展到新的领域
really expanding into new areas
另一件事是我们不暴露内部的东西
another thing is we do not expose internal stuff
例如，这是与wetpack的对比
this is for instance and contrast to wetpack
它允许你把所有东西都塞进去
which allows you to basically plug everything
这对于黑客来说是一种很酷的做法
which is kind of cool for hacking
但这意味着
but it means that
你不能轻易地做一个新的版本
you cannot just easily do a new release
因为每一个变化
because every change
每一个内部改动都不能破坏一些东西
every internal change cannot break something
你不能重命名东西，你不能轻易改进东西
you cannot rename stuff you cannot improve stuff easily
而我们并不想成为这样的人
and we didn't want to be there
所以在默认情况下
so by default
内部的东西是紧密的，而且是滚动的
internal stuff is close and roll up
以使我们能够保持边缘状态
to allow us to remain edge up
我们想关注的另一件事是
another thing we wanted to focus in
是
is
可配置性
configurability
所以我们对
so we make
所以我们对卷起的用途几乎不做任何假设
very few assumptions about what roll up is used for
这意味着卷积被用于
which means that roll up is used for
许多小众的使用案例
many niche use cases
这对我们来说是非常重要的
which is very important to us
因此，例如，你可以在浏览器中运行roll up
so for instance you can run roll up in a browser
你不能这样做
you cannot do this with
据我所知，许多其他的按钮都不能这样做
many other buttons as far as I know
我们希望保留这种能力
and we want to retain that ability
但最重要的是，我们有一个插件界面
but most importantly we have the plugin interface
一个稳定的、有据可查的
a stable well documented
一流的API
first class API
这个列表中缺少的可能是
what is missing on this list maybe
是开发经验
is develop experience
是的，开发人员的经验是非常重要的
and yes developer experience is very important
这对我们来说也很重要
it's also very important to us
但问题是如果你想
but the thing is if you want to
专注于开发人员的经验
focus on developer experience
你需要
you need
你需要对卷积的用途做出假设
to make assumptions about what roll up is used for
而这
and this
这与这里的其他一些目标有冲突
kind of conflict with some of the other goals here
现在我希望是，也许
now I hope was that maybe
与我们做出的其他决定
with the other decisions we made
思想家们会介入并
thought party developers will step in and
弥补这一差距
close that gap
而且有一些成功
and there was some success
所以，例如有tsdx，它是一个很好的工具，可以用于
so for instance there was tsdx which is a nice tool for
0冲突类型的好的库捆绑
0 conflict types good library bundling
我们类似的微型捆绑
our similarly micro bundle
来自Jason Miller
from Jason Miller
还有很多其他类似的工具
and there are many other tools like this
有一件事我们也很自豪，那就是stencil
one thing we're also very proud of a stencil
这是一个网络组件frayback
which is a web component frayback
他们并没有真正宣传它
they don't really advertise it
但Stencil在很大程度上是围绕着卷轴建立的
but stencil is built very much around roll up
它在这里做着繁重的工作
it's doing the heavy lifting here
你可以找到它，如果你的鸡巴深入到
and you can find it if you dick deepen
那份文件
that documentation
基本上roll up是它的核心所在
that basically roll up is at its core
但是wmr，尤其是wheat在做什么？
but what wmr and especially wheat were doing
这已经超出了我的恐惧
this was beyond my horror
最疯狂的希望
wildest hopes
当然我们也支持这个
and of course we support this
那么你如何建立一个伙伴关系呢？
so how do you create a partnership
所以我们开始
so we started
包括Wheat和WM地区的开发者在早期的时候
includingwheat and WM area developers early in
插件式API扩展，要求提供PDP
plug in API extensions asking for pdp
说："好吧，这对你来说有用吗？
saying okay does this work for you
你想用这个做什么
what you want to do with this
但同时
but also
小麦在API上进行了真正的扩展
wheat was really expanding on the API
增加新的功能
adding new features
我们开始
and we started
基本上
basically
移植他们的一些扩展到滚筒中
porting some of their extensions into roller
所以一个例子是插件钩子的顺序属性
so one example is the order attribute for plugins hooks
这是一种替代强制执行的方式
which is kind of a replacement for enforce
因为我认为enforce实际上是
because I think enforce is really
解决了一个错误层面的问题
solving an issue at the wrong level
但其主要思想是
but the main idea
是，人们应该能够
is that people should be able to
乘坐滚筒式插件而不是小麦式插件
ride roller plugins instead of wheat plugins
除非他们真的需要针对小麦
unless they really need to target wheat
因此，这把我们带到了未来
so this brings us to the future
你想从这里走到哪里？
where do you want to go from here
当然，下一步是滚动3
of course the next step is roll up 3
然后，这里还有更多的好功能
and thenthere are more nice features here
我想提到的一件事是
one thing maybe I want to mention is
每个大块的横幅照片变成一个序曲
per chunk banner photo into a outro
所以有一个选项
so there's an option
有一个选项，允许你在每个生成的块的顶部或底部注入代码
that allows you to inject code at the top or
在每一个生成的块的顶部或底部注入代码
bottom of each generated chunk
有了Roll Up 3，你现在就有能力
and with roll up 3 you have now the ability
基本上，在你做这个之前，你可以查看该块的内容
to basically look into that chunk before you do that
这是一个非常好的方法来添加导入
and this is a really great way to add imports
出口什么的
exports whatever
专门的日志记录
specialized logging
这也将
which will also
自动获得酱油地图的权利
automatically get sauce maps right
这是一个重要的事情
which is an important thing
我真的建议你研究一下这个
and I really recommend looking into this
如果你需要这个
if you need this
嗯
um
其他方面，Saucemap的处理也得到了改进
otherwise saucemap handling has been improved
默认值已被改进，特别是
default values have been improved especially
围绕漫画的相互操作
around commanches inter operation
而且我们还将浏览器与其他的软件分开。
and also we separate the browser built with
基本上削减了滚动安装的大小
basically cuts roll ups install size
到一半以下
to less than half
和
and
我们为什么要从这里开始呢？
why do we want to go from here
正如我所说，我们希望继续关注我们的优势
so as I said we want to keep focusing on our strengths
这当然是3个摇晃和代码优化
this is of course 3 shaking and code optimization
还有代码拆分
and also code splitting
所以我承诺的一件事是
so one thing I promised
下一步要做的事情
really to work on next
是增加一个选项
is to add an option
来定义一个最小分块大小的目标
to define a minimum chunk size target
这是许多人的要求
this was requested by many people
因为很明显，一个
because apparently one
问题是，我们有很多非常小的分块
issue is that we have a lot of very small chunks
和
and
我想实现的解决方案是合并小块的
the solution I want to implement is to merge small
块没有副作用
chunks do not have side effects
合并到具有类似依赖性的大块中
into larger chunks with similar dependencies
滚子已经知道一个小块是否有副作用了
roller already knows if a chunk has side effects
所以分析是存在的
so the analysis is there
我们只需要
we just need to
实现一个很好的算法来计算出
implement a nice algorithm to figure out
如何做到这一点
how to do that
这样你就没有什么开销了
so that you have very little overhead from this
当然，另一个问题是
another question of course is
我们是否想让卷起的速度更快
do we want to make roll up faster
当然我们也想这样做
and of course we want to do that
事情是这样的，在小麦的文档中说
the thing is like in the wheat documentation it says
我们不排除使用用于生产的
we won't rule out the possibility of using
为生产而构建的
es built for production
构建的可能性，当它在未来稳定了这些功能之后
builds when it stabilizes these features in the future
所以es build真的是在为我们的下一年做准备
so es built is really breathing up our next year
我们想继续作为小麦的构建工具。
and we want to stay the built tool for a wheat
绝对
definitely
所以是的
so yes
我们很愿意开始将滚筒
we are open to start converting roller
部分最终转换为本地代码
parts to native code eventually
如果我们这样做的话，可能不会是去
and if we do that it will probably not be go
它可能会生锈
it will likely be rusted
因为这个工具已经非常成熟了
because the tooling is very mature
然后我们可以使用swc作为我们的传递器
and then we could use swc as our passer
这显然暴露了很多我们需要的东西
which apparently exposes much of what we need
作为板条箱
as crates
而且
and
不，当然，我们
no but of course we
需要新的贡献者来完成这个任务
would need new contributors to pull this off
所以，如果你能流利地使用Rust，并且也许
so if you are fluent and rust and maybe
我知道一点javascript
I know a little javascript
那我们就可以谈谈
then maybe we can talk
我们很高兴能在这个项目上开始新的合作。
very happy to start new collaborations on this one
这就是我想谈的内容
and this is what I wanted to talk about
非常感谢您的聆听
thank you very much for listening
也许你学到了一些别的东西
maybe you learned something otherwise
也许我可以
maybe I could
用我们的儿童汽车收藏来取悦你
entertain you with our kids car collection
茜拉
Sierra